Lesson 36 The cost of government
36  政府的开支
First listen and then answer the following question.
听录音,然后回答以下问题.
What's the most important factor,both in government or business,
无论是政府还是企业,
for keeping running costs low?
保持运行费用较低的最重要因素是什么?
If a nation is essentialy disunited,it is left to the government to hold it together.
如果一个国家实际上处于分裂状态,使之联合起来就是政府的事了.
This increases the expense of government,
这样一来就增加了政府的开支,
and reduces correspondingly the amount of economic resources
从而相应地减少了
that could be used for developing the country.
可以用来发展国家的那部分经济资源.
And it should not be forgotten
不应忘记,
how small those resources are in a poor and backward country.
在一个贫穷落后的国家里那部分财力是很有限的.
Where the cost of government is high,
凡是政府管理费用高的地方,
resources for development are correspondingly low.
用于发展国家经济的资金就会相应地减少.
This may be illustrated by comparing the position of a nation
把国家的状况
with that of a private business enterprise.
同私人企业的状况加以比较,就可以看清这个问题.
incur: v.  承担
An enterprise has to incur certain costs and expenses in order to stay in business.
一个企业为了继续经营,不得不支出一定的费用和开销.
For our purposes,we are concerned only with one kind of cost--
就我们的目的而言,我们只关心一种费用--
administer: v.  管理
the cost of managing and administering the business.
企业行政管理费.
overheads: n.  一般费用
Such administrative overheads in a business
一家企业的这种行政管理开支
are analogous to the cost of government in a nation.
类似于一个国家的政府管理所用的开支.
overheads: n.  一般费用
The administrative overheads of a business are low to the extent
企业的管理费用会降低到相应的程度
that everyone working in the business can be trusted to behave in a way
如果企业中的每个人都在真诚地
that best promotes the interests of the firm.
为提高企业利润而工作的话.
If they can each be trusted to take such responsibilities,
如果企业的每个人都信得过,人人都认真负责,
initiative: n.  主动，积极性
and to exercise such initiative as falls within their sphere,
在各自的工作范围内发挥主动性,
overheads: n.  一般费用
then administrative overheads will be low.
行政管理费用就会降低.
It will be low because it will be necessary to have only one man looking after each job
行政管理费用降低的原因是:每项工作只需一个人去完成,
without having another man to check upon what he is doing,
用不着另外再有一个人检查他的工作,
keep him in line,and report on him to someone else.
督促他遵守章程,或向有关人士汇报他的工作.
But if no one can be trusted to act in a loyal and responsible manner towards his job,
但是,如果企业中谁也不可信赖会对工作尽忠守职
checker: n.  检查人员
then the business will require armies of administrators,checkers and foremen
那么企业就会需要大批的管理人员、检查人员和带班人员,
overheads: n.  一般费用
and administrative overheads will rise correspondingly.
管理费用就会相应地增加
overheads: n.  一般费用
As administrative overheads rise,
管理费用增加了,
so the earnings of the business after meeting the expense of admini stration,will fall;
那么在扣除管理费用后,企业的收入就降低了.
dividend: n.  红利
and the business will have less money to distribute as dividends
因而用于分红的金额
or invest directly in its future progress and development.
或直接用于将来开拓和发展的投资就相应地减少了
It is precisely the same with a nation.
一个国家的情况也完全相同.
To the extent that the people can be relied on
如果人民忠于职守,
to behave in a loyal and responsible manner
举止规矩,能受到政府的信赖
the government does not require armies of police and civil servants
那么政府就不需要大批的警察和文职人员
to keep them in order.
去促使人民遵纪守法.
But if a nation is disunited,the government cannot be sure
但是,如果一个国家处于分裂状态,政府不能相信
that the actions of the people will be in the interests of the nation;
人民的行动有利于国家,
and it will have to watch,check,and control the people accordingly.
那么政府就不得不对人民进行监督、检查和控制.
A disunited nation therefore
因此,一个处于分裂状态的国家
incur: v.  承担
has to incur unduly high costs of government.
必然要支付过高的行政管理费用.